# 嗨喽大家好
Hello, everyone!
# 今天我们做一个懒人排骨
Today we'll cook "Lazy Man's Pork Ribs".
# 然后这个是我四伯爷上午没有（卖）专门留起来的
Uncle kept these spareribs from his morning market sale.
# 他今天跟大家分享一个小技巧
He wants to share a tip with you today.
# 来嘛 四伯爷
Here, Uncle.
# 咋子搞啊
What should I say?
# 安
Eh?
# 你说咋个搞啊
Where do I start?
# 你说的都嘛 你说这块油是你故意留在上面的安
You said you intentionally kept this oily layer on.
# 你看 很多猪不像这块排骨
You see, many ribs don't look like this one.
# 你看我把它搞来就像百分之八十的那种排骨
If I remove this, it will look like 80 percent of ribs you see.
# 这里面这个朦朦（膜）啊
The membrane here.
# 你们买排骨你们必须要看到这个
Before you buy ribs, you must check whether it is there.
# 这个朦朦拿来就没意义得
It is useless.
# 这个肥朦朦
This greasy stuff.
# 就是肥油嘛
It's fat.
# 啊 肥油嘛
Yes, just fat.
# 这冷了就没得那么好抓得了
Difficult to remove now it's cold.
# 要刚刚
It should be removed...
# 要刚刚杀出来的时候
Be removed right after kill.
# 你们买排骨有多少人还不知道这个有的摊主他会把肥油留在上面
You know some butchers they don't remove this fat.
# 这个排骨吃起来非常腻
And the ribs taste greasy.
# 看嘛 很多他就懂不起 你看嘛这一层
See? Some don't know about this fact. It's all because of this layer.
# 这层肥油噶
This layer of fat.
# 这肥油刮来只有丢 我们屠宰场头
This fat is just waste at our slaughterhouse.
# 大家买排骨吃感觉很腻的话估计就是这层油给你留在上面了
Greasy ribs are very likely because of this layer of fat.
# 以后你们买排骨要看一下反面这一面
So you should check the bottom side when shopping for ribs.
# 不要有油的 有油的话要摊主把它给你撕掉
Let the butcher remove this fat if you see it.
# 你这不好整哦
It's difficult to remove.
# 不好整就算了
Let it be.
# 你看嘛这撕了就看得到这个肉
You can see the meat now.
# 没撕朦就看不到这个肉
Before we can't see the meat.
# 一哈吃得完啊
Isn't it too much for one meal?
# 吃不完打包
We can store the rest.
# 大块大块的砍咯
Chop in big chunks?
# 可以
Sure.
# 呀 好粗一根的
Yay! This one is big.
# 好 我们这个排骨就这样切大块一点
OK. We leave ribs in those big chunks.
# 下面来准备一下配料
Now we prepare the seasoning ingredients.
# 那么大一块的啊
Keep them that big?
# 烧出来它要缩 四伯爷
They will shrink once cooked, Uncle.
# 柠檬直接切片片
Slice some lemon.
# 好酸哦 我都闻到酸了
I can smell the sourness.
# 可以
Good.
# 好 再切一块姜
Now cut some ginger.
# 然后再来几根葱
Get some scallions.
# 给它卷起来就可以了
Wrap them around into a knot.
# 我去拿个盆盆来
I'll get a bowl.
# 我们把这个切好的全部丢进去
Put everything in.
# 然后调这个（料汁）
Now we prepare the sauce.
# 直接拿可乐来烧
I'm going to use coke.
# 我们这个直接放可乐
We use coke
# 因为这个既甜 然后烧出来比较香
because of its sweetness and flavor.
# 它这个可乐的话本身就有焦糖 也不用去调色
Coke has caramel that also colors food.
# 稍微多放一点可乐
A little bit more.
# 加点盐巴
Add some salt.
# 四伯爷你看到 比较神奇哈
Uncle, look. It's going to be interesting.
# 我们这个盐放下去它又会重新冒泡
Bubbles will appear once I add salt.
# 哦哟 跟烧的开水样
Wow, looks like it's boiling.
# 你们要说这个有多简单 就这么简单
Don't believe it? It's this simple.
# 然后我们再抓两把这个白糖下去
We add two handful of white sugar.
# 大概的话30克左右
About 30g.
# 然后直接这个倒进去这两个烧在一起就是
Then it's just a matter of cooking them together.
# 哦 好简单
Oh, that's easy.
# 所以叫懒人呢
That's why it's called a Lazy Man's dish.
# 嘿嘿 懒人安逸
Hehe, lazy man. Nice!
# 四伯爷你吃了还是要变懒人的哦
Uncle if you eat, you are going to become lazy.
# 我吃了二天变懒了 老子还要找你的麻烦
If I become lazy, you will be in trouble.
# 锅中加入适量的清水
Add water into the wok.
# 然后将排骨冷水下锅焯水
Then put in ribs with cold water and boil.
# 加入适量的料酒去腥
Add some cooking wine to remove the stinky smell of pork.
# 将调好的料汁倒入锅中
Pour the prepared sauce into the wok.
# 再将排骨下锅开大火烧开
Then add ribs and boil over high heat.
# 烧开之后再撇去浮沫
When boiling, remove the floating foams.
# 好 这哈就开小火慢慢烧
Good. Now we cook using low heat.
# 把这个水烧干 烧干了就可以了
Evaporate all the liquid and then it's done.
# 好了没有
It's ready?
# 没有 我把这个捡了
No, just picking these out.
# 把汤汁收浓就可以起锅了
Thicken the liquid and we are ready.
# 差不多了
Good enough.
# 尝哈我的懒人排骨 看你吃了变不变懒
Have a taste. See if you will be lazy.
# 嘿嘿
Hehe.
# 整没整脱骨的哦
It's not as tender as falling-off-the-bone.
# 嗯
Yes.
# 啃得动不哦
Is it chewy?
# 啃得动
Not so much.
# 点都不腻 虽然有点肥的都不腻
Not greasy at all. Even for the fat meat.
# 啃得动不嘛
Having trouble chewing?
# 干是好干
It's very dry.
# 就是没烧脱骨
But not tender.
# 有点硬 噶
A little bit hard?
# 嗯
Yes.
# 如果你们喜欢吃硬一点的话可以少烧一点时间
If you like chewy ribs, use less time cooking.
# 要是想吃软一点就多放点可乐
Add more coke if you want tender ribs.
# 我的牙口不好就只有慢慢地啃
My teeth stop me from eating. I have to take slow bites.
# 好吃
Yummy.
# 其实这个就是简单版本的糖醋排骨
This is simpler-version Sweet & Sour Pork Ribs.
# 比如没有放醋的话是放柠檬汁代替醋
Only we used lemon juice instead of vinegar.
# 然后糖的话就没有放那么多
And added not so much white sugar.
# 就是说特别简单嘛 适合不怎么费精力的人做
It's super easy to cook. Suitable for those who don't want to spend much time cooking.
# 所以叫做懒人排骨
That's why the name for it.
# 懒人排骨 安逸
Lazy Man's Pork Ribs. Nice!
# 不干了
I'm good.
# 我们这个菜没有放一滴油 就是因为排骨它自己会出油
We don't use any cooking oil, because the ribs contain much oil.
# 这个脆骨才好干
Gristle must be delicious.
# 脆生生的 你们牙口好吃起就安逸得很
They are crispy. Your teeth are good. You can enjoy.
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
Ok. This is all for this video.
# 拜拜
Bye bye.
# 你们伯爷的牙齿咬不动
The ribs are too hard for your Uncle's teeth.